We're back at the combine 2026 on radio
row with Charles Arbuckle. I'm Matt
Taylor and the headman, the head coach
of the Indianapolis Colts, Shane Stiken.
Nice enough to join us for a few minutes
taking time out of your busy schedule.
Let's start there. What What is the
combine like for you? How many different
uh balls are you juggling this week here
downtown at the convention center and
inside Lucas Oil?
>> Well, right now is a big media day with
you guys. So, going through that right
now. Um and then obviously after that
we'll go through our interviews. We have
our formal interviews with the players,
uh, the workouts, um, and we go through
that process obviously throughout the
week. Um, and that's where it's at right
now.
>> I mean, do you get a chance to breathe
is or is it just all football all the
time for
>> It's all football. We get just a little
break here and there to obviously grab a
bite to eat, but uh, it's basically
football and evaluating these players.
>> All right, speaking of evaluation, let's
start there. Daniel Jones, I'm sure you
had to evaluate him very high,
especially in those first 10 games of
the season, uh, when he was completely
healthy. I know you and I have talked a
lot about this over the course of the
year, but how much I know you can't say
anything in terms of contracts, but what
what did he mean to this offense and his
ability to help galvanize the locker
room and put it into a really good spot?
>> Yeah, he meant a lot uh obviously the
start that we got off to there uh at 8
and two was huge. Um and he was playing
winning football um for us and
completing passes and throwing
touchdowns and take care of the football
and we were winning games and uh what he
what he he was able to do in that
stretch was pretty impressive and
obviously had the leg injury you know
with the broken leg playing through that
and then obviously had the unfortunate
deal with an Achilles. Um but what he
was able to do for us was huge for us.
You know, coach, when you look at it
from the standpoint of the off season,
you being the play caller, self-couting
yourself, going back through and just
trying to figure out, hey, how can we
get better? How can I get better as a
play caller? What does that look like
for you once the season's over to now to
when the season starts?
>> Yeah, it's a good question. We'll go
through and I'll go back and watch every
game um through last year um starting
with the first one and just go through
it. Um obviously situations that could
come up in the game, you know, hey, this
situation comes up again, like maybe we
could have done this a little bit
better. Um, and that's a self- scout,
you know, reflection process that we go
through. And then also we go through,
um, we look around trends around the
league, around college football,
whatever that may be. You're always
trying to grow uh, and make sure you're
getting better as an offensive unit, uh,
whether it's scheme or whatever you're
doing, how you're practicing, and you're
always looking at self-reflection and
ways to grow and get better. And so, we
take that time uh, here uh, throughout
the offseason, you know, and then going
into spring with the players.
>> I know analytics play a big role, but
also probably feel or things that you
do. So tell us a little bit about that.
Just how you look at the analytics, get
the self scouting, and then this is what
I feel like we need to do.
>> Yeah, I've never really dove into this
in depth, but you guys are going to get
it good in depth about the analytics.
You know, I I I I use the analytics.
Obviously, they're a big part of the
game right now. And obviously, a part of
it is the fourth down decisions. A lot
of people, you know, if you go for it on
fourth down and it works, right, it's a
great call. If you don't, it's like,
what are we doing?
>> Um, but I think there is a time and a
place for it. You know, I think uh you
know, there's certain situations when
you are in your minus territory, you got
to be very smart in that situation. But
when you get around midfield and you're
at the 50 to the plus 40, you know, that
is a unique area. You know, it's a long
field goal. You're probably out of field
goal range. You probably don't want to
punt there cuz, you know, the field
position is not that big of a
difference. So, you got to be smart in
those situations. Uh and so that's when
the play calling comes into effect. You
know there's there was a game I think uh
two years ago um you know it was third
and whatever 14 at the you know I think
it was the minor or plus 48 and I'm like
well it's going to be hard to convert
this thing here so I'm going to call a
run here and get it hopefully to the 40
or whatever and cut it down and kick a
field goal and then you know next thing
you know we lost you know we didn't get
a yard and it was like why' you run it
there what are we doing an idiot you had
two downs in your mind
>> yeah in my mind I was like yeah we got
two downs you know cuz if we throw
incomplete right there. You're fourth
and 14 and so you're punting for sure.
So, hey, let's try to run it here and
then, hey, maybe we can go for it on
fourth down or we'll get it closer to a
field goal and you run it and you get no
yards and you got to punt. It's like,
what was that? Why would they run it
there? You know what I mean? So, there's
a lot of that that plays into it.
>> No doubt about it. Shane Stiken with us
here on radio row. We talked about
Daniel Jones. Again, I know you can't
talk about contracts, but Alec Pierce is
a big free agent as well.
>> A thou over a thousand yards on just 47
catches.
>> It's pretty impressive. That's that's
unbelievable. What did he mean? How many
different dynamics did he bring to the
offense to being able to unlock the
offense for it to be able to reach its
full potential?
>> Well, I mean, as we know, um, just from
a fans perspective and as we know as
coaches, his big playability is huge for
our offense. Um, his yards per catch, I
think, you know, the past two years he's
led the league in yards per catch. Um,
but he's also added the element, you
know, of the intermediate stuff to his
game as well. You know, the one-on- ones
on the outside, the in cuts, all that
stuff. Um he's he's continuing to grow
in that area and getting better uh every
year at doing that. I think Reggie's
done a hell of a job developing into
that
>> and he wasn't really known for that
>> prior to this year or at least we didn't
see it as much. How what what steps did
he take to make sure that was
>> prevalent part of his game?
>> Yeah, I think he did a hell of a job in
the offseason working on it. You know
what I mean? Coming out of his breaks,
working on certain routes that we wanted
to use him on because we know he's a
speed guy. So, if you can get guys
running down the field fast, these DBs
are going to turn and open their hips,
and then you can run the comebacks on
them one-on-one on the outside. Uh, get
them turning and run those inbreaking
cuts. And he did a hell of a job with
it.
>> Off season, you also had Marian Hobby,
who I played against when he was in New
England. I think that's a great pickup,
but also too, defense in this draft
could really pay dividends or free
agency. So, tell us a little bit about
what you see on the defensive side. We
always spend time with you on offense,
but you attack those guys every day.
>> Yeah, for sure. you know, I'm I'm
excited about our defense going into
next year. I think uh with Luke's scheme
going into year two in that system and
the guys feeling more comfortable with
that system and just the terminology and
the communication that happens from the
front to the linebackers to the back end
is going to be huge, you know, um for
our defense. But excited about our
defense. Obviously, Lu, he's coming on.
I'm really excited to make another jump,
you know, for him to make another jump
this year. Um, and obviously getting
Sauce, getting him healthy, obviously an
elite corner there, and then Cam Binham
and the rest of the pieces and getting,
you know, Buckner back healthy, uh, is
going to be big for us
>> in that regard. Do you feel like last
year was kind of an incomplete grade for
the defense, right? I don't want to take
away anything that anybody else did in
terms of personnel, but it's tough to
operate the defense the way you want it
when you don't have Buckner for nine 10
games and Saw Gardner out with the calf
and Ward with the three concussions,
right? I mean, it just felt like you
never really played with a full deck on
that side of the ball.
>> I think that's part of it, though. You
got to find ways to overcome that.
That's the NFL. There's going to be
injuries. There's going to be ups and
downs. And sometimes you got to find
ways to win ugly, you know, and
especially down the stretch there at the
end of the year. You know, we got to
find ways with what happened, those
uncertain, you know, those unfortunate
circumstances with injuries. We got to
find ways to win games 17 to 14, you
know what I mean? Or whatever it may be.
And uh and then we go from there. You
know, when you look back at that and you
and I think you hit the nail on the
head, what are some of the things the
guys have told you, hey, I could this is
what we can do just a little different
because coaching is one thing, but
players also have to play a role in
that.
>> Yeah, no doubt. I think those that's
that's kind of like our offseason study,
you know, as we go. Obviously, the
players, you know, you're you're into
the, you know, year evaluations with
those guys and they get out, but when
they come back in, it's kind of like
that's when those conversations really
take place, you know, with those guys
going forward. All right, doubling back
to offense. Uh Anthony Richardson
obviously dealt with the the fluke eye
injury before a game week six against
the Arizona Cardinals. Guess a
two-parter. Uh where is he at now? How
is he feeling? And then how does he
factor into your plans at quarterback
going forward?
>> Yeah, I think you know the the ice
progressing well. You know, I was really
proud of the way he went about his
business, you know, in training camp and
the way he was preparing and obviously
backing up Daniel and then obviously
having an unfortunate, you know, eye
injury, which was a freak deal that you
can't make up. Um, but I was really
proud of all that, the way he handled
that and so, you know, we'll see what
the future holds with him.
>> How proud of you were you of Riley
Leonard and the steps he took last year,
especially late in the year when he's
playing and getting a chance to play
against a Texans defense that was all
in? Tell us a little bit about that. You
know, I was really pleased with Riley
and the way he went about his business
but prepared. Um, obviously, you know,
being in that backup role all year, but
just learning and soaking in and taking
it in in like a sponge, you know, and
learning from Daniel. And then you get a
44 year old Philip Rivers to come in the
building and learn from him for a couple
weeks. Um, so I think that was big. And
then, you know, in the circumstances
that he played in, obviously went in
Jacksonville game when Daniel went down
and and played pretty well there. Um,
and then obviously, you know, finishing
out the year in Houston. Um, seeing that
was was was good. Coach, last couple of
things because I know you got to run,
but we really appreciate your time. I
guess just big picture. Are you are you
over the way the season ended last year?
I know it was disappointing, right?
Dropping the last seven, but I mean, how
do you seriously how do you
compartmentalize?
>> Yeah. No, I I obviously, you know, when
the when the season completely ends and
the Super Bowl's over, that's when it's
a like a reset, like, okay, good. Now
everyone's zero and zero and here we go
again and it's a new season and we got
to attack it the right way and work our
tails off you know this off seasonason
to get better and improve um you know
schematically uh roster-wise we're
always looking to get better in that way
and so I'm excited you know I'm very
optimistic for this season. I mean, do
you how do you how do you balance the we
were on fire, we were 8 and2, we were
clicking and humming, one of the best
teams in the NFL in those first 10
games, and then Daniel Jones, like you
said, comes up with the broken broken
leg, and then the schedule heats up, the
injuries start to hit. I mean, how do
you balance the on fire part versus the
disappointing part against the good
teams?
>> Yeah, I think, you know, obviously
you're the obviously the start of the
season was magical. It was special. you
know, you're on a heater for, you know,
10 weeks and you're rolling in top of
the division and the number one seed and
then you have the unfortunate
circumstances. But I think as a coach
too, you got to learn from that and grow
from that when those injuries do happen,
you know, and sometimes you can't
control those. They're part of the game
and uh you got to find ways to win ugly,
you know, and I think that's going to be
big part of what I look at going forward
if this does happen again and injuries
happen like, hey, how are we going to
win these games? How are we going to win
these tight games um going forward?
>> Did you watch the playoffs?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, did you I mean, what what
what aspects of the playoffs did you
take away in terms of how this team can
make those next steps going forward and
break through?
>> Yeah, I think obviously um obviously
just getting into the tournament is the
biggest part. Once you get in, I think
anyone has a chance in this league and I
think it's just getting there first. And
so once you get there, obviously you got
to be ready to roll uh in those
situations where you get in, but I
thought the playoffs were good. There
was some back and forth games obviously
and uh you know, it was fun to watch.
>> No doubt about it. S Gardner, he's an
Indianapolis Colt. He's your first round
pick here in 2026 and I know you're
excited about that. But the Colts
looking to make hay in rounds two and
beyond here uh upcoming in April. Coach,
I know you're busy. Crazy times here in
the combine, but we appreciate you
stopping by.
>> Awesome. Thick net.